DOMINIC SENGO

Software Engineer

P.O BOX 130, Kiminini, 30209 +254702060203 / +254745717922 dominicsengo@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

I am a Full-Stack software Engineer based in Nairobi. I have a keen eye for balancing beautiful design with accessibility and performance. I have used the MERN stack to build flexible front-end and backend marketing websites. As a solo developer on a marketing team, I am experienced in managing and executing on large projects. I am a patient communicator, a team player who brings a lot of laughter to a room, and someone who can quickly switch focus when priorities adjust.

SKILLS

- HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap
- JAMstack (Next.js, Contentful, Sanity, Vercel Functions, Netlify)
- MERNstack
- JavaScript, Typescript, React framework, jQuery, Ajax
- NodeJS, Express software APIs & SDKs, package management
- Python, Flask
- C Programming
- Dart, Flutter
- BASH
- MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLAlchemy, prisma
- Redis, MongoDB
- RESTFul APIs
- Paired programming, code reviews & team-based development
- Dynamic Programming
- Project scope management, sprint leader, Github project management
- Functional testing, Unit testing
- UX Design

EXPERIENCE

Freelancer - software developer

JANUARY 2020 - PRESENT

- Maintainer of website codebase & landing pages
- Lead large scale projects using Agile frameworks & Kanban boards, then work into weekly sprints to execute
- Built fully responsive, accessible web pages & components from designs
- Lead major codebase package update project
- Increase website performance scores
- Optimize codebase at each stage of the lifecycle to improve performance scores and load times
- Update content models in Contentful to ensure efficient & flexible workflow for content editors
- Write data migration scripts to integrate with Contentful's Management
 API to automate content upload tasks & content migrations
- Create flexible page templates to decrease page development times

County Government of TransNzoia, Kitale - IT Intern

JANUARY 2017 - MARCH 2017

- Invoicing of clients using E.R.P system LAIFOMS(Local Authority Information Financial Management System)
- Exposure to IPPD system(Integrated Personnel Payroll Data)
- Worked on IFMIS system(Integrated Finance Management Information System)
- Information security measures where i configured firewalls(cyberoam 200mg), servers and networks
- ICT help desk and Technical support

GAO Tek Inc, New York(Remote) - Software Developer Intern

APRIL 2023 - AUGUST 2023

- Developed and implemented new features for the company website using WordPress CMS, resulting in increase in user engagement.
- Created custom plugins and themes to extend the functionality of the WordPress platform.
- Provided technical support to website users, resolving over 100 issues per month with an average satisfaction rating of 95%.
- Collaborated with designers and content creators to ensure a consistent user experience.
- Utilized version control system (Git) to manage code changes and track progress.

 Enhanced my skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and WordPress development.

EDUCATION

ALX, Nairobi - Nanodegree

JUNE 2022 - AUGUST 2023

Attained Nanodegree software engineering with specialization in Backend

Andela, Nairobi - Nanodegree

JULY 2023 - OCTOBER 2023

Attained Nanodegree Front-end software development(React Learning Program)

Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology, Juja -

Diploma

SEPTEMBER 2015 - NOVEMBER 2019

Diploma in Information Technology - Attained Credit

Masaba Secondary School - KCSE

JANUARY 2010 - NOVEMBER 2014

KCSE - Attained C(Plain)

Pathfinder Academy - KCPE

2003 - 2009

KCPE - Attained 310 Marks

CERTIFICATIONS

Software Engineering Certification - ALX
React Learning Program - Andela
UX Design - Google
LinkedIn Learning

REFEREES

MAARTEN VAN MIDDELAAR - ALX SE Technical Mentor

https://www.linkedin.com/in/maarten-van-middelaar

SAMSON KIMANI - Founder JkClassics 0737 218 156